Patrick Bonner

Fullstack Developer

Contact: Patrickbonner0405@gmail.com

Seasoned Full Stack Developer with 9 years of experience, well-versed in numerous programming tools and languages. Proficient in both backend and frontend development. Highly effective at working on any part of the development process in an efficient and accurate manner.

| EDUCATION and Training

Colorado Technical University | Colorado Springs, CO

Computer Science

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science 2014

| Professional Experience

Freelance Software Engineer - Self-Employed

Jan 2023 - Present Time

Skills: NodeJS, Python, Express, Django, Handlebars, Jade, REST, GRPC, Flutter, React, React-Native GCP, AWS, Azure

Tasks:

- * Produced high-impact, user-friendly websites that accomplished all business goals.
- * Developed views and templates with Python and Django's view controller and templating language to create a user-friendly website interface.
- * Worked with clients to analyze computing and network needs and installed appropriate solutions.
- * Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features.
- * Completed IoT projects in Arduino, React as well as NodeJS
- * Built project structure for both backend and frontend and integrated Apollo GraphQL.
- * Learnt new technologies and languages including crypto currency, flutter/dart, etc.

Full Stack Engineer - Converse

Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

Skills: NodeJS, Express, REST, React, Jenkins, CI/CD, AWS

Tasks:

- * Successfully spearheaded the migration process from Node.js v12 to Node.js v20, ensuring compatibility, performance enhancement, and security compliance.
- * Conceptualized and developed a comprehensive Storybook framework tailored to Converse's specific needs, facilitating streamlined development, testing, and collaboration across teams.
- * Implemented a robust CI/CD pipeline utilizing Jenkins and AWS S3, optimizing the development lifecycle for rapid iteration, testing, and deployment.
- * Designed, built, and published NPM packages, enhancing code reusability, maintainability, and scalability across projects.

Senior Software Engineer - Achieve

Sep 2021 – Jan 2023

Skills: NodeJS, Express, REST, React, Contentful, Kafka, Confluent

Tasks:

- * Successfully integrated with Tealium along with home grown analytics module into lead acquisition web app to track user journey which in turn helped marketing team pull reports accurately
- * Translated product mockups into reusable UI components using React and Material UI in a next.js app
- * Created serverless APIs/endpoints in lead acquisition app which was built using next.js app, using MySQL as database server deployed to GCP using Kubernetes
- * Mentored and coached junior developers on implementing better processes and in any technical roadblocks.

Javascript Developer - True North IT Boulder

Dec 2017 – Nov 2021

Skills: Javascript, React, React-Native, Node, Express, Vue, RESTful, Micro Services, JSON, XML, Nginx, Apache, Linux, MacOS

Tasks:

- * API development using Express.js, Koa.js and asynchronous API for readable and intuitive code.
- * React / Redux, Vue / VueX UI development of features including Chart.js, D3.js implementations of candlestick and market depth data.
- * Tested and maintained core product software to provide optimization and reliable functionality for end users
- * Built and applied reusable code to other projects to reduce consulting fees and development hours.
- * Contributed back-end development experience and collaborated on multiple APIs crucial to functionality.
- * Created proof-of-concept prototype applications for demonstration and evaluation purposes.

Frontend Developer - Teletech Holdings

Mar 2015 – Aug 2017

Skills: Javascript, HTML, CSS

Tasks:

- * Collaborated with UI and UX persons to develop friendly and usable websites and web-based software.
- * Evaluated software development project plans and recommended adjustments.
- * Assisted clients and internal staff with troubleshooting to quickly resolve software issues.
- * Created and implemented tracking software with modules designed for specific client needs.
- * Contributed to small and medium size of micro-service development using Python and NodeJS

SKILLS

- Javascript (8 years and ongoing)
- Node (6 years and ongoing)
- React, Next (6 years and ongoing)
- Vue, Nuxt, AngularJS (3 years)
- Typescript (3 years and ongoing)
- Nest.js (2 years)
- Angular6+ (2 years and ongoing)
- Python, Flask, FastAPI, Django (6 years and ongoing)
- PHP, Laravel, CodeIgnitor (4 years and ongoing)
- MySQL, MonboDB (4 years and ongoing)
- SOAP, REST, gRPC, GraphQL
- Socket, Scrapping
- Agile Development Methodologies